Hello? Is that you, Chiba?
Huh? A movie?
Sorry, I've got plans to hit up
a recording studio with some friends.
Huh? But it's our day off.
We're free to do whatever, aren't we?
Besides, only couples go
to movies alone together.
I'm gonna hang up now.
Good grief, Chiba really needs
to get a girlfriend to go to the movies with.
All right. It's time to show
Naopei just how awesome I am.
Yo! If it isn't, Kabachi.
What are you doing out here?
Huh? Tokiwa?!
Headed to practice?
That's weird, most teams usually take
the last day of Golden Week off.
So why aren't you guys doing the same?
M-mind your own business!
Not everybody has it as easy as you!
That flippant attitude of yours
really gets under my skin!
I know we lost to your
team in the last tourney,
but my I scored way more
points than you overall.
Don't get too cocky.
Well yeah, I'm a point guard.
Oh, and by the way, I managed to pull off
a triple-double in that match.
For points, assists, and
steals, if I remember right.
So tell me, why are you guys headed this way?
Let me guess, is it a practice match?
A practice match with Kuzu High?
Really? Kuzu High, huh?
What's your problem?!
Don't look down on us
like we've fallen from grace or something!
I swear, you're one of
the rudest jerks I know!
We're just going for kicks
and giggles, that's all.
You know there's no way I'd get serious
against trash like Kuzu High.
Uh-huh, sure.
QUIT GIVING ME THAT LOOK, DAMMIT!
Taro always blows his top at guys
who have better looks than him, huh?
Well, there is some truth
to what he was saying.
I don't think we'll need to put too much effort
into this game against Kuzu High.
Oh, I just remembered, Konishi.
Don't you have a relative
who's getting married today?
You should've just taken
the day off and went.
It's fine.
I've actually been looking
forward to playing Kuzu High.
Ahiru no Sora
The Boys' Spirit
I'm sorry that it took so long.
I told you they'd be ready in time for the game,
but this is cutting it super close.
This is awesome! They're as good as new!
And I can't believe how clean they are now!
Yeah, we gave them a thorough cleaning.
But maybe that was going too far.
No way! This is great!
Now I won't get a hard
time for how they look!
Great, I'm glad to hear it.
So, you don't need mine anymore, right?
Oh, yeah.
Uh, can you wait just a sec?
Sorry, Nanao. Would you mind if I used those
for just one more day?
Huh? But we finally fixed up your old ones...
Yeah, but yours were really comfy to wear.
And more importantly,
I went through our whole training camp alongside
those shoes, so I want to use them until the end!
Kurumatani...
Are you sure?
Of course, as long as you're fine with it.
Okay, then please feel free to use them.
Uh, right, thanks very much.
What are you two even doing?
Kitasumi High is here!
Yo. Sorry to keep you guys waiting.
Wait, is that Tokiwa? But why?
Hey.
Why the hell did you tag along?!
Just felt like it.
Salt
Be gone, demon! Be gone!
Oh come on, let me be a spectator.
I promise that I won't get in the way.
Your mere presence causes enough problems
by taking everyone's eyes off of me!
So just get lost!
Seriously?
Don't be so mean, I ditched my band practice
just so I could come.
Hello again, Hanazono. It's been a long time.
Isn't that Konishi?
Huh? I don't think I know this guy.
Back in middle school,
he was a grade below us.
That weird kid who was always
tagging along with us.
Oh! Lil' Koni!
But damn, you must've
really hit a growth spurt.
How tall are you now?
196 centimeters, if you can believe it.
Oh yeah? So, I guess you kept
playing basketball, huh?
Yes. Thanks to your help.
Thanks to us? I don't even
remember doing anything.
I used to join you both
during your extended practice sessions at night.
Back then, I had no basketball
skills to speak of...
Momoharu would often take time
to teach me a variety of things.
And what about me?
Well Chiaki, you would always have me
fetch your snacks... and pay for them.
Goddammit, Chikai...
After you two left the team, most everybody else
just stopped taking the game seriously.
It was depressing.
But actually, from then until now,
I've never skipped a day of practice!
Wow, you're a real workaholic!
Nice, man. Keep it up.
Y-yes, sir!
Senpai...
Huh?
Basketball isn't some merciful sport
that you can just crawl back to...
...after you made the choice to drop out.
What?!
Say that again, punk.
Stop it, Momoharu.
This time to my face!
If you want to prove him wrong,
then do it out on the court.
Okay, then, please use this as a locker room.
If there's anything you need help with,
please feel free to ask.
She's a... major cutie!
You know, girls like her always
make the best managers!
Actually, it seems that she's
a member of the girls' team here.
Yeah, we already know their manager.
Isn't it supposed to be Taro's cousin?
Huh?
Speaking of, where'd he run off to?
I want to use them until the end!
What are you sitting here
hugging your shoes for?
Ouch!
Wait, I don't remember you
using shoes like those.
Uh, yeah, these are actually...
Whatever.
Anyway, I just wanted to make sure
you haven't forgotten our promise.
What promise?
Oh, don't be coy. We made a promise to go
to the amusement park together, right?
Yeah, but that was only if I found the time.
Oh please, you gave me that same line
during spring vacation.
Besides, places like that are usually for dates
and we're cousins.
It doesn't matter if we're cousins.
I am.... dead serious
about my feelings for you!
Stop being weird and giving
me that look, you jerk!
It's creeping me out!
She's so adorable.
Oh, there you are! Hey, Nanao!
I've been looking for you.
What is it?
Mr. Satsuki needs you.
The coach for the other
team came to greet us.
That's the shorty from before...
I recognize those shoes!
Whoa, what are they doing?
Looks like a circus performance.
That's a tip drill.
Anybody can do it with some simple practice.
They're so organized.
Yo, have you guys improved a bit?
Hey, Tokiwa.
We have!
I think if we played your team at Maru High again,
things would turn out differently!
I welcome the challenge.
Just so you know, the team that you're facing today
is strong in their own right.
So I've heard.
Their match against you guys
went all the way to overtime.
Our team's roster is heavily
comprised of seniors.
But Kitasumi relies more
upon freshman and sophomore players,
which means they're only
going to get stronger.
It's hard to say that we could win a second time
if we had to face them again.
And above all...
...he's the player you really
need to be careful of.
He may not exactly look it,
but his talent for basketball is top-tier.
Especially when it comes to points,
he's always the one who scores the most.
To be frank, I don't think I stand a chance
against him in a one-on-one.
Even you, Tokiwa?
In fact, that guy alone managed
to score 50 points against our team.
I imagine what will decide the outcome of this game
is whether you can stop him or not.
50 points...
Oops, sorry about that.
I'm hyped to play against
someone so impressive!
Here.
I thought I'd let this be a
learning experience for you.
But it turns out, I'm going
to have to bring my A-game.
Huh?
Listen up, squirt! You're
not on anybody's radar!
The only winner here is me!
I'm not gonna lose!
I'm really feeling it now, you know?
This is so much more nerve wracking
than our Maru High match.
You said it!
That's fine and all, but please tell me you guys
actually memorized the damn rules this time.
Dude, I've got them all down pat!
We're not allowed to move
while holding the ball.
We're not allowed to do
any punching or kicking.
And, uh, what else was there?
Perfect, just how I like it.
Well, that's a surprise. The other team
isn't wearing any uniforms at all.
All right then, boys. I suppose you don't have
to bother wearing your uniforms, either.
Huh? Are you sure about that, coach?
It makes us look silly
if we're the only ones going all out, right?
Let's just get this over
with and head home. Okay?
If you're going to be such a wet blanket,
then why did you even accept this match?
Cut me some slack, Taro said he was going to quit
if I didn't go through with it.
You guys wouldn't be happy
if Taro just left the team, right?
Anyway, take a look at that.
Oh jeez, there's always at least one fool
who loves pretending that he's in the NBA.
And despite how they may look,
they always totally suck. Without fail.
I mean, come on, are we supposed
to believe he's got a tattoo or somet-?
GREASED
LIGHTNING
Uh, hello. What's up, Juri?
Sorry, do you mind calling
me back a little later?
I've got really important plans right now.
Basketball isn't some merciful sport
that you can just crawl back to...
...after you made the choice to drop out.
Damn cocky punk.
Just you wait, I gonna
make you eat those words!
I love you. Please go out with me.
Huh?
Oops, that came out wrong!
I was trying to say, "I'm gonna do my best!"
You can just forget all about
that other thing I said, okay?
Like really, don't worry your
pretty little head about it.
Seriously, for real, you don't
need to even think it over!
Enough blabbering! Just get out there!
All right, I need to put my heart into this.
For the sake of love.
Hey Kurumatani!
It's time to line up, hurry!
Oh, sorry! I'm coming!
Kurumatani.
You can do it!
Totally! Just you watch!
Okay, everyone. We will now begin the match!
I need all players to come
to the center circle!
Kanagawa School of Medical Science
Secondary Hospital
Say, Ms. Yabuuchi?
Yes?
Do you think I could get permission
to leave here just for a bit?
You already know that's impossible.
The doctor made that crystal clear, no?
That's why I'm asking
you. It'll be our secret.
I promise to keep my mouth shut, okay?
If I agreed to something like
that I'd be fired immediately!
Is there something special
that you have going on today?
Uh... well, not really.
It's nothing much, but even so.
I've got a game starting now...
gonna win for sure.
Get moving!
All right!
Whoa, so high!
How do you like them apples?!
Kuzu High #4! Jump ball violation!
Huh?!
Momoharu...
Hold up, what even makes that a foul?
It was a violation, not a foul.
The ball must reach the apex of its toss
on a jump ball before anybody can touch it.
Forget about it! We've
only just gotten started!
Keep your heads in the game!
Gah! They just scored one
on us like it was nothing!
Sorry, guys!
You have to keep a closer
eye on the other team!
That was a perfect play. We
knew this wouldn't be easy.
They're really good.
Do we actually stand a chance against them?
You can do it, guys! Just remember
everything that we practiced!
Oh, right!
It's our first possession,
let's take it slow.
A man-to-man defense from half-court, eh?
Incredible!
Not only did he anticipate
#11 throwing off the defense,
but also that #4's movements would create
the perfect blind spot to get a pass through.
It bounced!
You damn klutz!
That pass came at me way too hard,
learn how to hold back a little!
Don't let him shoot, Konishi!
On it!
Yes! I blocked him!
He pulled a double clutch
from that position?!
It looked like he was already halfway
behind the backboard!
I don't believe it...
So, they found a new forward?
He's got a great feel for the game.
It's more than just their point guard,
the entire team has improved their offense.
It's crazy to think they were essentially
just a team of amateurs until recently.
Sweet! Another basket for us!
A steal!
What was that, Katori?!
You're doing a pretty
solid job out there, Kite.
Remind me to pay you later.
For real?
Hold up! I just know you're gonna steal it
from my piggy bank again!
Their center has a lot of jump height!
Don't let him in the paint!
Keep your eyes on #11 for sure!
Don't let him shake you off!
That sign means...
Setting up the Nabe Screen!
Taro! You've got a screen behind you!
Say what?
Hmph, too easy.
It'll take a lot more
than that to shake me...
He nailed it!
Nice one, Nabe!
Oh? They've really gotten
themselves into good shape.
Switch!
Idiots. We're not gonna let such an obvious screen
get the better of us.
He's fast!
I guess he wasn't just
bragging when he said things
would turn out differently
if we played again.
It seems that Kabachi has the right idea.
None of us can afford to be
taking it easy right now.
Sakata, call us a timeout. Right now.
Huh? But the game has barely started, sir!
I know, it's fine.
Timeout by Kitasumi High!
What's the deal, coach?
You realize we're barely a
minute into the game, right?
Boys, go and put your uniforms back on.
I'm benching our starting lineup
so you can all redo your warm-ups.
We won't... hold anything back.
You're sure slow on the uptake, gramps.
The coach should be the last one
to need a damn pep talk.
We were ready to put everything
into this game from the very start!
My apologies. I will admit this was a failure
on my part as your coach.
I never expected to be
bushwhacked so close to home.
If we don't strike while the iron is hot,
it may come back to bite us.
We'll start with man-to-man
and see how our opponent reacts.
Everyone make sure you know
who you're supposed to be guarding.
I'm on #10!
I've got #6.
None of the Kitasumi players are specialized
3-point shooters like Kurumatani,
so we can afford to ease
up our defense a little.
But please be wary of #7 in
any and all circumstances.
He won't hesitate to try and score
from both long and short range.
We have shut him down before
he finds his sweet spot.
#7... That's who I'm guarding...
The timeout has now ended!
Okay! Let's really get this party started!
They've gotten serious about this.
Which means everything before
was just a simple warm-up, huh?
Kitsumiyoshi | Kuzuryu
Kitasumi ball! Throw-in!
Nabe, stay on #10 as best you can!
Deny them any passes!
And make sure you stay alert for screens!
I've got #7 all covered!
So you're my defender, eh?
Never thought I'd get matched
up with such a shorty.
You'll regret underestimating me.
Oh please, you're the shortest one
on your entire team, Kabachi.
That's enough of the pot
calling the kettle black!
What irks me more are those shoes!
My shoes?
Yeah, I remember them from a year ago...
Hey, I recognize those. They're
a limited-edition color.
Yeah, but I'm worried that
they look tacky on me.
Why worry about that? I think
they look just fine on you.
Really?!
That makes me happy! Thanks!
KAPOW!
Up until then, she had just been
one of my childish cousins.
But after that moment,
she became a woman inside my heart.
Taro! You're holding onto
the ball for too long!
The shot clock will run out!
I consider those shoes a gift from an angel above,
who led me to true love!
And now this little bastard...
...has his dirty feet all over them!
I'll win them back.
And rekindle the memories of our love!
Awesome! A between-the-legs dribble!
Between-the-legs into a spin.
It's the same move he used before!
No, wait!
He's gonna charge in! Don't let him through!
He went straight for a jump shot?!
And boom goes the dynamite!
24-second violation!
The basket doesn't count!
What?! No way!
Are you sure I just didn't barely make it?!
Ugh, I was so close! Dammit!
Quit yapping so much.
Am I crazy, or did he just
blow a kiss to somebody?
If he hadn't wasted time, that
shot would have counted...
No kidding, one of those spins
was totally unnecessary...
Play with style.
That's my motto, you know!
That was a really clean cut to the middle.
Not to mention that he actually looked away
from the basket, but still sunk the shot.
I guess he's not just the
idiot he seems to be.
He's good.
Uh-oh.
Sorry, that came up short!
Rebound!
Glad to see you're pulling
your weight, Senpai!
Oh, shut up!
Nice one, Kite!
Kitsumiyoshi | Kuzuryu
That puts us ahead by 5!
Yo. What's the matter, Konishi?
You were talking tough shit before,
but you've hardly done anything on the court.
Go for it! Kitasumi for the win!
We need to shore up our
defense in the middle!
Taro, don't do anything stupid this time!
I won't let him past me this time.
I didn't do all that defense
practice for nothing!
It doesn't matter how
much height he has on me!
You dumbass! She told us
to expect shots from long range!
Momoharu, get the rebound!
Shit, you guys are running me ragged!
He boxed him out!
This bastard!
I can't even make him budge!
The one who taught me how to do this...
was you, Momoharu.
Loose ball!
What the hell?!
You had one job, Momoharu!
Not happening!
Crap... he waited to shoot...!
That little snot... he took his sweet time
to get the foul call!
Defensive foul on #7!
The basket counts! One free-throw!
Holy crap...
So, uh, that dude is starting
to seem kind of badass.
He's more than he seems.
This guy is... the real deal!
Ahiru no Sora
Next Time: The Best Start and the Worst Start
Next Time: "The Best Start
and the Worst Start."